Welcome. In the last lecture, we successfully set up the capsule trace to trace the surfaces
欢迎。在上一节课中，我们成功地设置了胶囊追踪器来追踪我们的角色前面的表面
in front of our character. And in this lecture, we'll take care of tracing from eye height.
在我们的角色面前。在本课中，我们将从眼睛的高度进行追踪。
Now that we already have a way to obtain the surface info in front of us, we'll also need
现在我们已经有了一种方法来获得我们面前的表面信息，我们还需要
to take care of the scenario too. So this only needs to be a line trace, and it needs
也需要处理一下这个场景。所以这只是一个线条追踪，而且需要
to start from our eye height. This is the same kind of trace that we'll use later to
从我们的眼睛高度开始。这也是我们稍后要用的一种跟踪方式，用来
determine whether or not the character has reached the ledge during climbing. Let's look
来确定角色在攀爬过程中是否到达了壁架。让我们来看看
at how we can set this up. Go back to my project. I'm going to close my project and go to Visual
看看我们如何设置这个。回到我的项目中去。我将关闭我的项目并转到Visual
Studio. The line trace we use will be very similar as this capsule trace. So I'm going
Studio。我们使用的行跟踪将与这个胶囊跟踪非常相似。所以我将
to create another function inside of this region. It's going to return an F hit result. I'm
在这个区域内创建另一个函数。它将会返回一个F的命中结果。我将
going to call this function to line trace single by object. And its input parameters
我将调用这个函数来逐条追踪对象。它的输入参数
are going to be the same as above. So we'll need to fill in the star, the end, and whether
将与上面一样。所以我们需要填入星星、结尾，以及是否要显示调试形状。
or not we want to show the debug shape. And I'm going to create a function definition,
我们是否要显示调试形状。然后我将创建一个函数定义、
put it below this capsule trace. So the function that we need to use is also inside of this
把它放在这个胶囊跟踪的下面。所以我们需要使用的函数也在这个
UCSMA system library. And it's called line trace single for objects. And the input parameters
UCSMA系统库中。它被称为对象的行跟踪单。而我们需要填写的输入参数
that we need to fill in are very similar as these ones above. So I'm going to copy all
我们需要填入的参数与上面这些参数非常相似。所以我将复制所有
of them and I'm going to paste them in here. So for this one, we need to fill in the star
并把它们粘贴到这里。所以，对于这个，我们需要填上星号
and the end. And the third parameter will be the object types. So we don't need this
和结尾。而第三个参数将是对象的类型。所以我们不需要这个
radius and half height. I'm going to delete both of them. And unlike the capsule trace,
半径和半高。我要把它们都删除。而且与胶囊追踪不同的是、
in here we only need to fill in a single out hit result. So let's create one. So it's going
在这里，我们只需要填入一个单一的出击结果。所以让我们来创建一个。所以它将会是
to be an F hit result. I'm going to call it out hit, then fill in this out hit. And this
它将是一个F的命中结果。我将把它称为 "出击"，然后填入这个出击。而这
function simply needs to return this out hit. And I'm going to add a semicolon in here.
函数只需要返回这个打出。我将在这里添加一个分号。
All right. This is the trace function that we can use multiple times. And I'm going to
好的。这就是我们可以多次使用的跟踪函数。而我将会
create another function to trace from high height. So under this trace climbable surfaces,
创建另一个函数，从高处追踪。所以在这个追踪可攀登的表面下、
I'm going to create another new function. I'm going to call it trace from high height.
我将创建另一个新的函数。我将把它称为从高处追踪。
And it's going to have two input parameters. The first one is going to be a float. I'm
它将会有两个输入参数。第一个将是一个浮点。我将
going to call it trace distance. The second one is going to be another float. I'm going
我把它叫做跟踪距离。第二个参数是另一个浮点数。我将会
to call it trace start offset. And I'm going to give it a default value of zero point F.
称之为跟踪开始偏移。我将给它一个零点F的默认值。
All right, I'm going to create a function definition below this function. And first thing I'm going
好的，我将在这个函数下面创建一个函数定义。首先，我将
to create a local variable is going to be a const F vector. I'm going to call this one
创建一个局部变量，它将是一个常量F向量。我将把这个称为一个
component location. It's going to equal to updated component get component location.
分量的位置。它将等于更新的分量获得分量位置。
So this is the component location. And in order to trace from our eye height, we'll
所以这就是分量位置。为了从我们的眼睛高度进行追踪，我们将需要知道我们到底需要多少。
need to know exactly how much we need to offset the trace start. So I'm going to create another
我们需要确切地知道我们需要将追踪的起点偏移多少。所以我将创建另一个
const F vector. I'm going to call this one eye height offset. So this will be the updated
常量F向量。我将把这个称为眼高偏移。所以这将是更新的
component get a vector. Now we have a vector that's pointing up. I'm going to multiply
分量得到一个向量。现在我们有一个朝上的向量。我将把这个向量与眼高相乘
this vector with the eye height. There's another variable from the parent class that we can
这个向量与眼睛的高度相乘。还有一个来自父类的变量，我们可以使用它。
use and it's called character owner. So this is the character owner of this character movement
它被称为角色所有者。所以这就是这个角色运动组件的角色所有者。
component and we can use this to access the base eye height. And you can see here it says
部件的所有者，我们可以用它来访问基本眼高。你可以在这里看到它说
pointer to incomplete class type is not allowed. So we'll need to include the character class.
不允许使用指向不完整类类型的指针。所以我们需要包括角色类。
And for that I'm going to directly include our climbing system character.h. So I'm going
为此我将直接包括我们的攀登系统character.h。所以我将
to go to its cpp file, copy this include and paste it to this cpp file. And here you can
转到它的cpp文件，复制这个include并粘贴到这个cpp文件。在这里你可以
see I have some red squiggles. So that means we'll need to include the folder name of this
看到我有一些红色的斜线。所以这意味着我们需要包括这个头文件的文件夹名称
header file. And you can see this file is under the folder climbing system. So let's
头文件的文件夹名称。而且你可以看到这个文件是在文件夹爬行系统下。所以让我们
add that. I'm going to copy this climbing system, put it in front of this name and add a slash.
添加它。我要复制这个攀登系统，把它放在这个名字的前面，然后加一个斜线。
And now we should be able to access the base eye height. So I'm going to type in base eye
现在我们应该可以访问基础眼高了。所以我将输入基础眼高
height and I'm going to add the trace start offset to this value. So later when we're
高度，并在这个值上加上轨迹开始的偏移。所以以后当我们在
climbing we'll need to use this function to detect the ledge. I'm going to add the semicolon
攀登时，我们需要使用这个函数来检测壁架。我要把分号加在
after it. By default this variable has a value of zero. Keep that in mind. Now that we have
在它后面。默认情况下，这个变量的值为零。牢牢记住这一点。现在，我们有了
the eye offset we have our line trace start. So I'm going to create another const f vector.
眼睛的偏移量，我们就有了我们的线迹开始。所以我将创建另一个常量f向量。
I'm going to call it start and the start is going to be component location plus eye height
我将把它称为起始点，起始点将是组件的位置加上眼睛的高度
offset. And for our line trace end it's going to be another const f vector and this start
偏移。对于我们的线迹终点，它将是另一个常量f向量，这个开始
is going to be our start plus this updated component. I'm going to get hold of this forward
将是我们的起点加上这个更新的分量。我将掌握这个向前的
vector multiply this vector with our trace distance. So this is our line trace end. All
向量与我们的跟踪距离相乘。所以这就是我们的线迹终点。所有的
right. I'm going to call the function that we just created. So you'll be able to do line
好的。我将调用我们刚刚创建的函数。所以你将能够做线
trace single by object. I'm going to fill in the start, the end and fill in true for
单个对象的跟踪。我将填入起点和终点，并将 "true "填入
draw debug shape. And same as our capsule trace I'm going to call this function inside
绘制调试形状。和我们的胶囊追踪一样，我现在要调用这个函数在
of the tick for now. So copy this one and paste it in here. And we'll need to manually fill
的函数。所以，复制这个函数并把它粘贴到这里。我们将需要手动填写
in the trace distance. Here I'm going to give it a hard code value of 100 units. You can
追踪距离。在这里，我将给它一个硬编码值100单位。你可以
create another member variable for this if you like. All right. I'm going to press control
如果你愿意，可以为它创建另一个成员变量。好的。我将按控制键
plus B to compile. I have a successful compile. I'm going to launch my editor back. Go back
加B来编译。我有一个成功的编译。我将启动我的编辑器回来。回到
to my project. I'm going to press play and you can see we have another line shooting
到我的项目。我将按下播放键，你可以看到我们有另一个行的拍摄
straight from our character's eye height. And now if I move to this surface we are getting
直接从我们的角色的眼睛高度。现在如果我移动到这个表面，我们会得到
two hit results. One is from the eye height trace. One is from the capsule trace. And
两种结果。一个是来自眼睛高度的追踪。一个是来自太空舱的追踪。而且
that's great. Now we should have all the information, all the tools we need to check whether or not
这很好。现在我们应该有所有的信息，所有的工具，我们需要检查是否
we can start climbing. And we'll look at how we can do that in the next lecture. Later
我们可以开始爬升。我们将在下一讲中研究如何做到这一点。稍后
when you implement this by yourself, this is the math that I use for our eye height trace.
当你自己实现这一点时，这是我为我们的眼睛高度追踪所使用的数学方法。
The trace start offset here, later when we try to detect the ledge, simply tracing from
追踪开始的偏移量在这里，以后当我们试图检测壁架时，简单地从我们的眼睛高度来追踪
our eye height will be not high enough. So this is what this trace start offset is here
我们的眼睛高度将不够高。所以这就是这个追踪起始偏移量的作用
for. Other than that, everything should be pretty straightforward. Feel free to refer
的作用。除此以外，一切都应该是非常直接的。如果你需要帮助，可以随时参考
back to the video if you need help. And I'll see you in the next lecture.
如果你需要帮助的话，可以回到视频中。我们在下一节课再见。
[music]
[音乐]